Sorry I'm late. Did I miss anything?
抱歉遲到了 有錯過什麼精彩好戲嗎？
Joey stuffing fifteen Oreos in his mouth.
喬伊在嘴裡塞了15片餅乾
Fifteen?
15片？
Your personal best!
刷新個人紀錄哦
Where were you?
你到哪兒去了？
On a date.
約會
I met this girl on a train going to a museum upstate.
我去逛博物館 在火車上認識了一個女孩
-Which museum? -How'd you meet her?
哪間博物館？ 你是怎麼認識她的？
No. Answer his.
回答他的問題比較好
We were at the back of the train.
我們坐在車廂最後面
I sat near the door so she'd have to pass by me...
我的座位靠門
...if she wanted to switch cars. She was totally at my mercy.
她要換車的話得先經過我 她得任由我擺佈
Were you so late because you were burying this woman?
你遲到是因為 在埋她的屍體嗎？
I'm late because she lives in Poughkeepsie.
我遲到是因為她住在波啟浦夕
She seems great, but she's two and a half hours away.
她人很好，可惜住得太遠
How can she be great if she's from Poughkeepsie?
她是波啟浦夕人 怎麼可能好到哪兒去？
That joke would have killed in Albany.
這個笑話在艾爾班尼 會搏得滿堂彩
Done! I did it.
成功！
Who's stupid now?
還覺得我是個傻蛋嗎？
The One with the Girl From Poughkeepsie
本集播出：亂點鴛鴦譜
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Look! They're lighting the big Christmas tree tonight.
看，今天是聖誕樹的點燈之夜
That paper is two weeks old.
那是兩周前的報紙耶
Who keeps leaving old newspapers in the trash?
是誰老是把舊報紙 丟在垃圾桶裡的？
I really wanted to take Kathy to this.
人家好想帶凱西去看
At least you have somebody to miss stuff with.
至少你還有伴和你一起錯過
I hate being alone this time of year.
我討厭過節時孤伶伶的
Next it's Valentine's Day...
情人節、
...then my birthday,then bang!
我的日生轉眼就到 然後…
Before you know it,they're lighting that damn tree again.
他們又要點亮那棵 討厭的聖誕樹
I want somebody!
我想找個伴
You know,I want a man!
我想找個男人
It doesn't even have to be a big relationship. Just a fling!
我不想談轟轟烈烈的戀愛 來段露水姻緣就好了
I didn't think girls ever just wanted a fling.
沒想到你也想要露水姻緣
Let me tell you,it's been a long time since I've been flung.
告訴你，我缺水缺得可久了
I know what I'm giving you for Christmas.
那我知道聖誕節要送你什麼了
There are nice guys in my office. Want me to set you up?
我有幾個同事挺不錯的 要不要幫你介紹一下？
I've been single a long time. Why haven't you offered before?
我單身了好一陣子 你以前怎麼沒提出這個建議？
I have a girlfriend. I'm happy.
我現在有女朋友，很快樂
I no longer go out of my way to stop others from being happy.
不需要再處心積慮 破壞別人的好事
Okay.
好
No accountants.
我不要會計師
And no one from "legal." I don't like boring jobs.
也不要法律部門的人 我不喜歡工作無聊的男人
And Ross was what? A lion tamer?
難不成羅斯是訓獸師嗎？
What's wrong,Mon?
怎麼回事？
Everybody at work still hates me.
餐廳裡的人 還是把我視為眼中釘
Is it because of the review you wrote or something new?
是因為你寫的評論 還是有新的原因？
It's the review.
一定是因為那篇評論
I was making headway.
我還以為漸入佳境
Everyone was smiling at me, and then I get off work...
大家都衝著我微笑 下班後才發現
...and find out they wrote this on my chef's hat.
他們在我帽子上寫了這個…
「婊子，快辭職！」
Maybe they meant to write "Quiet,Bitch."
也許他們想寫的是 「婊子，快住嘴」
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Fine! Just trying to be nice.
幹嘛？火氣這麼大
I haven't been picked on this much since kindergarten.
我幼稚園畢業後 就沒受過這等鳥氣
And they brought in someone from junior high to do the see-saw with me.
當時他們找了個高中生 來跟我玩翹翹板
They're trying to make me quit. If it were any other job,I would.
他們無所不用其極的 想逼我辭職 換做是別的工作我早就不幹了
But I've waited for this my whole life.
但我等當主廚等了大半輩子
Wait,you're the boss. Yell at them. Or fire them!
等等，你是老大 你為什麼不吼他們 或乾脆炒了他們？
I would love to,but I can't. I'm not good at confrontation.
我也很想這樣 但我最不會處理衝突場面
You know what you can do?
你知道你要怎麼做？
I read about this director, Orson Welles...
名導奧森威爾斯在片子開拍前
...who,at the beginning,would hire somebody just to fire them.
都會刻意花錢請一個人
Then they would all know who was boss.
為的就是當著大家的面開除他 好殺雞儆猴
I'm not doing anything. Why not fire me?
我反正沒事 你乾脆開除我算了
It's a good idea. Can you waiter?
好主意 你知道怎麼當服務生嗎？
Good enough to get fired.
反正你要開除我 管那麼多幹嘛
All right. You're hired!
好，我決定用你了
That's why I got fired last week! Does Orson Welles direct commercials?
難怪我上個禮拜被開除 奧森威爾斯導不導廣告片？
Yes.
有
I say,Drew? Are you seeing anybody right now?
德魯，你有在跟誰交往嗎？
I'm not asking for me.
我不是幫我自己問啦
I'm not gay. I'm not asking you out.
我不是同志，不是在約你
I'm not gay.
我不是同志
I didn't think you were gay.
我以前沒把你當同志 不過現在覺得有點像
I do now.
My friend,Rachel, wants to be set up.
我朋友瑞秋 希望我幫她介紹個男人
I just got out of a big relationship.
我才剛剛跟前女友分手
I'm not looking to get serious.
還沒準備好要談感情
That's okay. A fling might be all right with her.
就算只是春風一度也沒關係 瑞秋不會有意見的
Is this "Hot Rachel" that you took to the Christmas Party?
等等… 你說的是來參加耶誕派對的 火辣瑞秋嗎？
By the way,that is her full name.
沒錯，那就是她的本名
Wow! I'm free for her.
我有空，幫我介紹一下吧
Wait,I didn't say I wasn't free.
等等，我又沒說我沒空
Let's talk it over at the Ranger game.
這樣吧，咱們邊看球賽邊聊
Hold on. I just got a box of Cubans.
我有一盒古巴雪茄
I'll bring them by your office at five.
我五點鐘拿到你辦公室去
That's a little later than I usually stay,but sure.
我平常不會待到這麼晚 不過可以破個例
Before the game,we could enjoy some eight-year-old Basil Haydens.
咱們在看球賽之前 可以先喝上兩杯 陳年海登威士忌
I don't know what that is, but that's a pretty nice jacket.
天曉得那是什麼東東 不過你的外套我看了挺順眼的
Kind of like that tie too.
領帶也不錯
Keep your pants on,man.
褲子就不必了
I'm writing a holiday song for everyone. Do you want to hear it?
我為大家寫了首聖誕歌 想不想聽？
Happy Hanukkah,Monica
摩妮卡，光明節快樂
May your Christmas be snowy,Joey
喬伊，願你聖誕節瑞雪紛飛
Happy New Year,Chandler and Ross
錢德、羅斯，新年快樂
Spin the dreidel,Rachel
瑞秋，快來玩陀螺
Pheebs,that's great!
真好聽
But you know, Rachel doesn't rhyme with dreidel.
但是瑞秋跟陀螺不押韻
I know,but it's so hard. Nothing rhymes with your stupid name!
我知道 但是要找跟你那笨名字 押韻的東西太難了
What are you talking about? Lots of things rhyme with Rachel:
跟瑞秋押韻的字多得很
Bagel,mail,jail,bail,cable.
如貝果、信件 監獄、保釋金、第四台…
Maypole.
五月節花柱…
All good. Thanks.
那些都不錯，謝了
Do you,maybe,have a nickname that's easier to rhyme?
你有沒有比較 容易押韻的外號？
Didn't your dad used to call you "Pumpkin"?
你爸以前 不是常叫你小南瓜嗎？
Pumpkin? But did he ever call you "Budolph"?
小南瓜不錯 但他有沒有叫過你布道夫？
Hello,children.
大家好
Have I got the 50 guys for you!
我幫你找了50個好男人
-Really? -I showed them your picture.
我不過把你的照片亮給他們看
Guys are throwing themselves at me and giving me stuff.
他們就窮拍我的馬屁 請我喝酒，送我東西
-Knicks tonight? -Where are the seats?
今晚想不想看尼克隊的球賽？ 當然，第幾排？
Wherever! I've got 20.
隨你挑，我有20張票
Will I like any of these guys?
我會喜歡你幫我挑的男人嗎？
You know,I'm going to...
我想...
...play the field a little bit more.
...再多觀察一陣子 錢德
Guys are signing over their 401 Ks to me.
他們對我簡直是 一個口令一個動作
You work with robots?
你的同事都是機器人啊？
Yes.
對
One guy,Patrick,you'll like him. He's nice,funny and a swimmer.
你一定會喜歡我同事派崔克 他人好、風趣 還是個游泳高手
I like swimmers' bodies.
我愛死游泳選手的體格了
His dad made the magnetic strip on credit cards.
而且他老爸還發明了 信用卡背面的磁條
I like credit cards!
我也愛死信用卡了
I'm not bad at this!
我還蠻會當紅娘的
-What does he do? -He works in fine foods.
他是做什麼的？ 他在美食部上班
-You have a fine foods division? -It's a big company....
你們公司有美食部？ 敝公司很大…
Now,wait a second. You make food and robots?
等等… 你們公司生產食物和機器人？
No,the robots just work for them.
不是啦，機器人在那裡工作
All right,I'm going to work.
我要去工作了
Does anybody have a problem with that?
有人有意見嗎？
Yeah,lady. I do!
小姐，我有意見
I got a problem!
你想雞蛋裡挑骨頭
I'll give you a problem!
就別怪我不客氣了
What will you do? Fire me?
你想怎樣？開除我？
You bet your ass I'll fire you!
那還用說
-See you later. -Thanks.
回頭見 謝謝
I should go. I've got a date.
我得走了，今晚有約會
With who?
跟誰？
You know the girl who lives in Poughkeepsie?
還記得那個住在 波啟浦夕的女孩嗎？
Not her.
不是她
This is someone else.
我又認識了一個女孩
I can't decide between the two.
現在左右為難
The one from Poughkeepsie,though two hours away,is pretty...
波啟浦夕那個女孩雖然住得遠
...really smart and a lot of fun.
但漂亮、聰明又有趣
But this other girl, she lives right uptown.
但另一個女孩…就住在上城區
She's just as pretty.
她也很漂亮
I guess she's smart.
應該也蠻聰明的
She's not fun.
但是無趣得要命
If she's no fun, why date her at all?
那你為什麼還要跟她約會？
I want to give her a chance. She lives so close.
我想再給她一個機會 因為她家實在太近了
And,at the end of the date, she said something that...
上次她說了一句話…
...if she was kidding, was very funny.
若她在開玩笑就好笑到不行
If she wasn't kidding,she's not fun. She's stupid and racist.
否則她不僅無聊、愚蠢 又有種族歧視
How was your first day at the restaurant?
第一天在餐廳工作的 情況如何？
Damn!
可惡
What happened to your fancy jacket?
你的制服怎麼了？
They baked it.
被他們烤了
I can't take this anymore.
我再也受不了了
-I'm going to fire you tonight. -You got it.
我今晚就要開除你 沒問題
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
You're still on fire there.
你衣服上還有火星
I think you got it!
你應該已經拍滅了吧
Chandler,you have the best taste in men.
錢德，你對男人的品味一流
Like father,like son.
虎父無犬子嘛
Patrick and I had such a great time last night!
派崔克和我昨晚玩得好開心
This could,maybe,get serious.
說不定能發展出一段 認真的感情
I thought you weren't looking for serious. Just a fling?
認真的感情？ 你不是要露水姻緣嗎？
Well,you know,possibly.
有可能噢
You didn't tell him that, though,right?
你沒告訴他吧？
沒…有
You told this guy that I was looking for a fling?
你告訴他 我想找一段露水姻緣？
-You don't tell him that! -Why not?
你怎麼能告訴他？ 為什麼不行？
I'd be thrilled if some hot girl
若某個辣妹只想來段露水姻緣 我高興都來不及…
I see.
我明白了
You telling him I want a fling and me putting out...
你告訴他我不打算認真
...he's so going to get the wrong idea!
咱們第一次約會時 我又火力全開 他一定會誤會的
Joey,could you pass the cheese?
喬伊，把乳酪拿來好嗎？
行
I'd prefer you didn't call me Joey.
可不可不要叫我喬伊？
I thought it might be fun to try out a cool nickname.
因為我幫自己 取了個超炫的外號
Hey,Dragon!
龍哥
Here's your tips from Monday and Tuesday.
這是你這兩天賺的小費
There's $300 in this one.
天啊，有三百塊耶
People get generous around the holidays.
是啊 過節時客人總是特別大方
And it never hurts to wear tight trousers.
穿緊身褲的效果更是棒到不行
Could the waiters listen to the specials?
請服務生過來聽聽今晚的特餐
There's Chilean sea bass with a mango relish
今晚有芒果醃鱸魚…
Why is nobody writing these?
你們怎麼都不做筆記？
We can remember them.
我們用背的就行了
Because you'll make up fake specials and make me cook them?
還是要隨口亂謅好整我？
Sure,that too.
那也行
Forget the specials for a minute. Here's the thing....
特餐的事先別說了 是這樣的…
For the last two weeks I have...
過去兩周...
...tried hard to create a positive atmosphere.
...我試著想營造一個 愉快的工作環境
Can't hear you!
聽不到！
Positive atmosphere.
愉快的工作環境
But I've had it up to here.
但是我的氣已經滿到這裡來了
From now on, it is going to be my way...
從現在開始 不聽我話的人...
...or the highway. All right?
...就滾蛋
Does anybody have a problem with that?
有人有意見嗎？
Hey,new guy.
菜鳥
I said,does anybody have a problem with that?
我說有人有意見嗎？
No,ma'am.
沒有
He has a name. It's Dragon.
他有名字，他叫龍哥
You want to know your name? Check your hat.
你想知道你的名字嗎？ 看看你的帽子
We did the hat,right?
我們有在帽子上寫字吧？
-What the hell just happened? -I am so sorry.
剛剛那是怎麼回事？ 真的很抱歉
I was going to do it.
我真的很想配合你
But I was standing there with $327 in one hand...
但我一手拿著327塊
...and $238 in the other. And I was thinking...
另一手拿著238塊...
...it's been a long time since I had...
我很久沒拿到…
...$327 plus $238!
327塊加238塊 這麼多錢了
We had a deal! It's why you're here. I've got to fire you!
我們說好的 我用你就是為了開除你
And I got to pay rent!
但是我得付房租
How about you don't fire me.
這樣吧，你別開除我
Instead,I stay. I gain their trust.
我留在這裡爭取他們的信任
They'll listen to the nice things I say about you.
我說你的好話 他們就聽得進去了
What nice things?
什麼好話？
Nothing yet. They hate you, and I want to fit in.
還沒有，他們討厭死你了 我想跟他們打成一片
Happy Hannukah,Chandler and Monica Merry,merry
錢德、摩妮卡，光明節快樂…聖誕…
You know what,Pheebs?
菲比，你知道嗎？
I'm not Jewish so....
我不是猶太人，所以…
Ross doesn't decorate his tree with floss...
羅斯也不用牙線裝飾聖誕樹
...but he's not complaining.
你有聽到他抱怨嗎？
Bad dream?
做惡夢啦？
I wasn't sleeping.
我又沒在睡覺
What was Phoebe's song about?
是嗎？ 那菲比剛剛在唱什麼歌？
It's the one with the cat.
在唱那首貓歌
I got to go. I've got another date.
我得走了，又有約
Did you pick one yet?
你決定要挑哪一個了嗎？
It turns out the one from uptown was making a joke.
沒有，上城區那個女孩 那次的確在開玩笑
It was a different joke. It wasn't that funny.
但是和我想像中的不同 而且沒那麼好笑
So I'm still torn.
我還是左右為難
You don't like the one from uptown.
你並不喜歡上城區那個女孩
And you're exhausted from dating Poughkeepsie.
為了跟波啟浦夕妞約會 又累得半死
Just end them both!
把她們兩個都甩了
Go to Poughkeepsie and break up with her.
坐火車去波啟浦夕跟她分手
Then break up with uptown.
回程跟上城妞分手
By the time you get home, you're done!
到家時一切都解決了
You're right. Thank you.
你說得對，謝謝
I had a similar problem when I lived in Prague.
我在布拉格也碰過這種問題
-Prague? -So much you don't know.
布拉格？ 我的事你不知道的可多了
Patrick just ended things with me.
派崔克剛剛跟我分手了
Did you or didn't you tell him I wanted a serious relationship?
你有沒有告訴他 我想認真談段感情？
I did! I absolutely did!
我有，我真的有
You idiot!
你這個白癡
I'm sure you're right. But why?
有道理，為什麼？
You don't tell a guy that you want a serious relationship.
千萬不能告訴男人 你要談段認真的感情
Now you scared him away!
你把他嚇跑了
I am sorry. I am so sorry.
對不起…
You should never be allowed to talk to people!
應該禁止你跟別人說話
I know,I know!
我知道…
Now I'm right back where I started.
我現在又回到原點了
This sucks!
粉難過
Being alone sucks!
孤孤單單的真難過
You'll meet somebody.
你遲早會遇見意中人
You're a great catch!
你棒呆了
When I told those guys about you, I didn't have to lie once.
我跟同事形容你時 一句謊話都沒說
Really?
真的嗎？
You graduated magna cum laude,right?
你畢業時 有拿優秀畢業生獎吧？
It doesn't matter.
沒有 不要緊
I got tickets to the Ranger game. You want to come with me?
我有兩張今晚球賽的門票 要不要跟我去看？
Cute guys in little shorts?
看猛男穿短褲滿場飛？
Sure.
當然要去
Actually,it's a hockey team. Angry Canadians with no teeth.
今晚是冰上曲棍球賽 你只能看到 沒牙的暴躁加拿大佬
That sounds fun too. Thank you.
好像挺好玩的，謝謝
Okay.
Have you ever been with a woman?
你有跟女人在一起過嗎？
What? What is the matter with you?
什麼？ 你有毛病
There is no good time to ask that question.
不管什麼時候問這個問題 都會被人罵
The station is Poughkeepsie. Poughkeepsie!
下一站是波啟浦夕…
Ross? Ross?
羅斯？ 羅斯？
Wake up!
醒醒
I need more swordfish.
再拿點魚來
-Can you get me more swordfish? -I don't speak English.
能不能再拿點魚來？ 我不講英文
-You just did. -I don't know what to tell you.
你剛講的就是英文 這下我啞口無言了
Fine.
好吧
Okay. Very funny.
很幽默
Let me out,please.
快放我出來
Come on,I'm cold!
裡面好冷
And covered in marinara sauce!
而且全身都是醬汁
Let me out!
放我出去
You found that handle,did you?
找到把手啦？
-It's not funny. -Well,that's not true.
不好笑 怎麼不好笑？
I'm a good person. And I'm a good chef.
我是個好人，也是個好廚師
And I don't deserve to have marinara sauce all over me!
我不該被弄得全身都是醬汁
If you want me to quit this bad then
若你們這麼希望我辭職…
Chef Geller?
蓋勒主廚
You know that speech you made?
還記得那天你講的那段話嗎？
I got a problem with it!
我有意見
-You do? -You bet I do!
是嗎？ 沒錯
I just wasn't listening then, that's all.
只是我那時沒專心聽
If you want a problem, I'll give you a problem!
你想雞蛋裡挑骨頭 就別怪我不客氣了
What are you going to do? Fire me?
你想怎樣？開除我？
You bet I'll fire you! Get out of my kitchen!
那還用說，滾出我的廚房！
Get out!
滾！
All right.
這才像話
Anybody else got a problem?
還有誰有意見？
How about you,chuckles?
你沒有意見？
You think this is funny now?
你現在還覺得好笑嗎？
What if I dance covered in sauce? You think it's funny?
我全身沾滿醬汁跳舞… 好不好笑？
No,it's really good.
不，你跳得很好
Take those salads to table four.
沙拉送去給四號桌的客人
And you,get the swordfish!
你去幫我拿魚
And you!
還有你…
Get a haircut!
去剪頭髮
Last stop,Montreal. The stop is Montreal!
終點站蒙特婁…
What?
什麼？
I bet myself that you had beautiful eyes.
我跟自己打賭 賭你有一對美目
Now that I see them,I win!
看來…我贏了
We're at my stop. Would you like to have coffee?
我要在這站下車 你想不想喝杯咖啡？
Are we really in Montreal?
我們真的在蒙特婁嗎？
Yes,we are.
對
So coffee?
想不想喝咖啡？
Coffee sounds great.
好主意
Wait.
等等
So you live in Montreal?
你住在蒙特婁？
No,but it's only a two-hour ferry ride to Nova Scotia.
不，我住新斯科細亞省 坐渡輪兩小時就到了
I should have thought about my wife and kids...
在我頂嘴之前
...before I talked back to Chef Geller.
真該想想家中妻小
It will be a lean Christmas at the Dragon house this year.
謝了 看來咱們龍府今年得過個 冷颼颼的聖誕節
Enough!
夠了
Lean,lean,lean!
冷颼颼啊
So this is a very special holiday song...
接下來是我為...
...that I wrote for some very important people to me.
...幾位好朋友 寫的聖誕歌
Went to the store Sat on Santa's lap
我去店裡坐在聖誕老公公膝頭
Asked him to bring my friends All kinds of crap
要他送堆禮物給我朋友
Said all you need is To write them a song
他說你只需要幫他們寫首歌
Now you haven't heard it yet So don't try to sing along
這首歌你們沒聽過 別想跟著我唱
No,don't sing along
不要跟我唱
Monica,Monica
摩妮卡…
Have a happy Hannukah
光明節快樂
Saw Santa Claus
我看到聖誕老公公
He said hello to Ross
他要我跟羅斯說哈羅
And please tell Joey
請告訴喬伊
Christmas will be snowy
聖誕節將瑞雪紛飛
And Rachel and Chandler
還有瑞秋和錢德…
Happy holidays,everybody!
祝各位佳節快樂